Guide to the Frank Durkan Papers AIA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Frank Durkan Papers
1920, 1970-2005
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Durkan, Frank, 1930-2006
Durkan, Monica
AIA.008
35.75 Linear Feet in 34 record cartons, 1 oversize flat box, and 2 media boxes
Frank Durkan (1930-2006) was a New York-based Irish American attorney active in legal cases and human rights issues related to Northern Ireland. He was a central player on the U.S. end of the Northern Ireland Peace Process, particularly in his role as Chairman of the political pressure group Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA). The papers reflect those activities, including the granting of a visa to Sinn Fein President Gerry Adams in 1994, the Good Friday Agreement in 1998, and decommissioning efforts down to 2002 document his work as an attorney with O'Dwyer & Bernstien law firm in New York. Durkan was widely consulted on deportation and extradition cases involving Irish Americans living in the United States and the collection documents the defense efforts mounted on behalf of his clients, particularly between 1991 and 2001. The collection also contains material of a personal nature on topics of interest to Durkan, including the Great Famine in Ireland, shipwrecks of Irish coming to the Americas, his membership and activities in the Irish History Roundtable and a collection of his books, legal, history and sports-related. A small amount of audio visual material completes the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers with the exception of files including attorney work-product and attorney-client privileged information. These folders are marked "RESTRICTED" and have been physically separated from the collection, but are intellectually arranged within their appropriate series and/or subseries.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Monica Durkan in 2007; additional accessions were donated in 2014 and 2018. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1997.039, 2014.006, and 2018.111.
Historical Note
Frank Durkan (1930-2006), a native of Co. Mayo, was a New York-based Irish American attorney active in legal cases and human rights issues related to Northern Ireland. He was a central player on the U.S. end of the Northern Ireland Peace Process, particularly in his role as Chairman of the political pressure group Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA). In addition, Durkan was widely consulted on deportation and extradition cases involving Irish Americans living in the United States; his papers document the defense efforts mounted on behalf of dozens of men, particularly between 1991 and 2001.
Francis Patrick Durkan was born in Bohola, Co. Mayo, Ireland on 13 August 1930, the second son of Bernard Durkan, a teacher, and Mary Rose O'Dwyer. He was educated at St. Nathy's in Ballaghadereen, Co. Mayo until emigrating (at age 17) to New York City in 1947, where two of his maternal uncles William and Paul O'Dwyer were already prominent members of municipal government and legal circles. Durkan earned his bachelor's degree from Columbia University in 1951 followed by a law degree from New York Law School in 1953. He worked for the family firm of O'Dwyer & Bernstien, starting as a clerk and rising to senior partner. During his distinguished law career, he represented cases of injury, negligence, and malpractice but became best known for his work defending Irish Americans in civil rights matters related to the conflict in Northern Ireland.
He succeeded in preventing the extradition of Desmond Mackin in 1981 – that decision is a landmark in the field of Extradition Law – and successfully defended the Fort Worth Five in 1973 and George Harrison in 1982 against charges of gun-running for the Provisional IRA. He was also consulted on several other important deportation, extradition, and Irish prisoner cases that followed the Harrison trial, including Joe Doherty who was represented by Steve Sommerstein and Mary Pike between 1982-1992.
Frank Durkan cut his socio-political eye-teeth at the elbow of his uncle Paul O'Dwyer, a towering figure in the Mayo Society of New York, the United Irish Counties Association, the American League for an Undivided Ireland, and the Irish Institute. Paul O'Dwyer (1907-1998) was also President of the New York City Council (1974-1977). His uncle, William O'Dwyer (1890-1964) was mayor of New York City from 1946-1950.
Durkan was known and respected across a spectrum of the New York Irish community through some of these same organizations. In addition, he was a founding member of the Brehon Law Society of the City of New York (est. 1978) and the Irish American Unity Conference (est. 1983), both dedicated to working towards the extension of human rights in the north of Ireland. In 1992 Durkan helped organize Irish-Americans for Clinton-Gore with Congressman Bruce Morrison (D-CT), the co-sponsor of H.R. 4300 (Immigration Act of 1990), as its first Chairman. After the election of President Bill Clinton, this group became Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA), a less partisan and more inclusive organization that monitored the Clinton Administration's Irish campaign promises, worked closely with the Ad Hoc Committee for Irish Affairs in Congress, and was a key player in the Northern Ireland peace process. Durkan had been Chairman of ANIA for four years when he was the Mayo Society of New York's Millennium Honoree and 'Mayo Man of the Year' in 2000. The history of the peace process in Northern Ireland, as it has been written since 1998, focused on 'stars' like George Mitchell, Jean Kennedy Smith, and William J. Flynn. The intense, behind-the-scenes work of groups like ANIA has been overlooked. The Frank Durkan Papers offer insight into the significant network of key relationships and perseverance in the United States that enabled dialogue to begin and continue in the north of Ireland during the 1990s.
Frank Durkan died on November 16, 2006 due to complications from a lung infection. He was survived by his wife, Monica Goggin, and daughters Mary Louise and Aisling.
Related Archival Materials
George Harrison Papers (AIA 009)
Jane Conlon Muller Oral History Collection (AIA 012)
Irish Immigration Reform Movement Records (AIA 016)
Irish Institute Papers (AIA 020)
Irish Republicanism Collection (AIA 022)
Patrick Daughton Collection (AIA 055)
Paul O'Dwyer Papers (AIA 069)
Scope and Contents
This collection document the professional work and social and organizational activities of Frank Durkan. Durkan was a lawyer in the firm O'Dwyer & Bernstien and the materials in the collection contain papers from significant cases in his career, including Desmond Mackin, George Harrison, and the Brooklyn Five. His membership and involvement in organizations such as Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA) and the Behon Law Society, as well as other activist organizations focused on conflict in Northern Ireland are also present. Durkan was also widely consulted on deportation and extradition cases involving Irish Americans living in the United States; his collection illustrates the defense efforts mounted on behalf of dozens of men in this situation, particularly between 1991 and 2001.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Northern Ireland -- History -- 1969-1994.; Extradition -- United States.; Deportation |z United States.; Northern Ireland |x History |y 1994-; Federal government records.; Legal assistance to prisoners -- United States.; Political prisoners -- Ireland.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Legal files.; Lawyers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Irish Americans.; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- New York -- Political activity.; Clan-na-Gael; Irish Republican Army; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; Flannery, Michael, 1902-1994; Irish Northern Aid Committee; Harrison, George, 1915-2004; The Irish people; Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, 1919-1980.; Durkan, Monica
- Series I: Northern Ireland and Activism, 1987-2005, 297636
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains material on organizations and activities pertaining to Northern Ireland. Americans for a New Irish Agenda was established from the previous group, Irish-American for Clinton-Gore. After Clinton was elected as president, ANIA was established with Durkan as Chairman to monitor Clinton's work on behalf of Irish-Americans especially as pertaining to promises he made during his campaign. These files are arranged chronologically. Other organizations represented include Irish American Unity Conference and Irish Northern Aid.
  - American Committee for Ulster Justice, Dec 1994; 582824 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Correspondence, 1981-1982; 582825 (Box 32, Folder 3, Folder 2)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Governance, 1981; 582826 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Hunger Strikes / H-Block, 1981; 582827 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Labor Statement on Northern Ireland, circa 1981-1982; 582828 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Media Coverage of Northern Ireland, 1981-1983; 582829 (Box 32, Folder 7, Folder 8)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Meetings, 1981-1982; 582830 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1981; 582831 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Ian Paisley, Dec 1981; 582832 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - American Irish Unity Committee: Symposium on Northern Ireland, Jul 1981; 582833 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): "Terrorist Group Profiles", 1988-1993; 582834 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Letter to Margaret Thatcher, Apr 23, 1990; 582835 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Amnesty International Report "United Kingdom: Human Rights Concerns", Jun 1991; 582836 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Transition Team, 1992; 582837 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Constitution, 1993; 582838 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Irish-Americans for Clinton-Gore (recommendations), Feb 1993; 297645 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Correspondence and Press, Mar 1993; 582839 (Box 32, Folder 20, Folder 21, Folder 18, Folder 19)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Correspondence re: Robinson visit to Belfast; Thatcher at William & Mary, 1993; 297646 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Jul 1993-Aug 1993; 582840 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Special Envoy to Northern Ireland Campaign, Aug 1993-Sep 1993; 582841 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Oct 1993-Nov 1993; 582842 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Protest Demonstration, Nov 1993; 582843 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): "Northern Ireland: The Changing Paradigm: Politics and the Constitution" by Padraig O'Malley, Nov 1993-Dec 1993; 582844 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Joint Declaration on Northern Ireland (Downing Street Declaration), Dec 1993; 582845 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Report on the Northern Ireland Investment Bill (New York State), Dec 1993; 582846 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Dec 1993-Jan 1994; 582847 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Jan 1994-Feb 1994; 582848 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Apr 1993-Jul 1994; 582851 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, May 1994; 582852 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Aug 1994-Sep 1994; 582853 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Human Rights Watch/Helsinki Report on Northern Ireland, Mar 1994; 582849 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes and Correspondence, 1994; 297647 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Gerry Adams Visit, 1993-1995; 582850 (Box 32, Folder 32, Folder 33)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes and Correspondence, 1995; 297648 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Feb 1995-Mar 1995; 582854 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): White House Conference for Trade and Investment in Ireland, Jun 1995; 582855 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Jul 1995-Aug 1995; 582856 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Clinton-Gore Re-election, Jul 12, 1995; 582857 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): President Clinton's Irish Trip, 29 Nov 1995-1 Dec 1995; 297649 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Letters to President Clinton, 1995; 582858 (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Jan 1996-May 1996; 297650 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Meeting with the White House (Agenda), May 1996-Jun 1996; 297651 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Meeting at White House (Correspondence and Press), Jul 1996-Dec 1996; 297652 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): MacBride Principles, Clinton Veto, Mar 1996-May 1997; 297653 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Deportations, 1997; 297654 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, 1997; 297655 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): A Message to Prime Minister Tony Blair from Irish Americans, 1998; 297656 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Declaration on Human Rights by Irish American Organizations, Dec 1997; 297657 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Jan 1998-Feb 1998; 299725 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Ad Hoc Committee for Irish Affairs, Jan 1998-May 1998; 299771 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Mar 1998-Apr 1998; 299772 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, Press, May 1998-Oct 1998; 299773 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, Nov 1998-Dec 1998; 299774 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence and Press, 1999; 299775 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Northern Ireland, The Equality Agenda Conference, Mar 1999; 299776 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, 2000-2005; 299777 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Americans for a New Irish Agenda (ANIA): U.S. Presidential Race, 2000; 299780 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Amnesty International: "United Kingdom: Human Rights Concerns", Jun 1991; 582859 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Anglo-Irish Agreement, 1985; 582860 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Boyle, Francis Anthony. "The Future of International Law and American Foreign Policiy", Oct 21, 1988; 582861 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Bunreacht na hEireann, 1980; 582862 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Clan na Gael: Constitution and Ritual, 1999; 299782 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Council of Europe: European Court of Human Rights: "Case of Ireland Against the United Kingdom: Judgment", Jan 18, 1978; 582863 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Harvey, Richard J. "The Right of the People of the Whole of Ireland to Self-Determination, Unity, Sovereignty, and Independence", 1990; 582864 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - "International Law and the Export of Terrorism," US Department of State Bulletin, Dec 4, 1972; 582865 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - "Ireland's Right to Sovereignty, Independence, and Unity is Inalienable and Indefeasible", 1985; 582866 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Irish American Activism (Other): Irish Coalition, 1997-1998; 299785 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Irish American Activism (Other): Activist Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999; 299786 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Irish American Activism (Other): Unity in Action Committee (Puerto Rico Prisoners), 1999-2005; 299787 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Irish American Information Service, 1994; 582867 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Irish American Information Service, Jan-Apr 1995; 582868 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Irish American Information Service, May 1995-Aug 1995; 582869 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Tim Pat Coogan, Aug 1993-Sep 1993; 582870 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Eliot Engel, Sep 1993; 582871 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Invitations, Jul 1993-Oct 1993; 582872 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Bobby McVeigh, Jan 1993; 582873 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Planning Meetings, Apr 1993-Oct 1993; 582874 (Box 33, Folder 17, Folder 16)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Planning Meetings, Sep 1993-Oct 1993; 582875 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Planning Meetings, Jun 1993-Sep 1993; 582876 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Planning Meetings, Sep 1993; 582877 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Planning Meetings, Mar 1993-Oct 1993; 582878 (Box 33, Folder 22, Folder 21)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Press Releases, Jul 1993-Oct 1993; 582879 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: 1993 Convention: Program, Oct 1993; 582880 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Minutes, Correspondence, and Press, 1994; 582881 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Minutes, Correspondence, and Press Releases, Mar 1994-May 1994; 582882 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Bob Linnon, Mar 1994-May 1994; 582883 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Correspondence, Press Releases, and Newsletters, May 1994-Nov 1994; 582884 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Correspondence, Press Releases, and Newsletters, Dec 1994-Feb 1995; 582885 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Correspondence, Press Releases, and Newsletters, Mar 1995-Sep 1995; 582886 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: British Telecom - MCI Merger, 1997; 299784 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Irish American Unity Conference: Correspondence; Convention programs, 1997-2005; 327648 (Box 1, Folder 27A)
  - Irish American Leaders Call for Truth on Bloody Sunday, Jan 1997; 299783 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Irish Arts Center, undated; 582887 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Irish Northern Aid: Organization Info and Communication, 1989-2002; 299778 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Irish Northern Aid: Press Clippings, Bulletins, 1989-2002; 299779 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Irish Northern Aid: Michael Flannery Memorial Booklets, 1996-2004; 299781 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Irish Northern Aid: Testimonial Dinner, New York City, 1997-2002; 327737 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ministry of Defense: Northern Ireland Future Terrorist Trends [RESTRICTED], 1978-1979; 582964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Materials are closed.
  - Norwegian Helsinki Committee: "Irish Terrorism or British Colonialism?: The Violation of Human Rights in Northern Ireland", Jul 1990; 582889 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Oifig Eire Nua, Dec 12, 1994; 582888 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Press: Clippings and Articles, 1987-1995; 299796 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Press: The New Republic Magazine, Feb 1995; 299797 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Press: Clippings, 1996; 299798 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Press: Clippings and Articles, 1994-1997; 299799 (Box 33, Folder 34, Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Republican Sinn Fein Poblachtach, Oct 1994; 582890 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - The Trial of the IRA Five by Tom Cox, 1984-1989; 582891 (Box 33, Folder 36, Folder 37, Folder 38, Folder 39)
  - Vietnam, 1987; 582892 (Box 33, Folder 40)
- Series II: MacBride Principles, 1984-2002, 297637
  - Amnesty International Reports (UK), 1992-1994; 299847 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Corporations List, Jun 1986; 299843 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1995-2002; 299848 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Investment Responsibility in Northern Ireland", undated; 299851 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The MacBride Principles: Genesis and History and The Story to Date", Jun 1993; 299846 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Northern Ireland: The Magnified Mirror" (report), May 1995; 299849 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets, 1986, undated; 299850 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Press, 1984-1993; 299844 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Status Report (New York), Feb 1989; 299845 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series III: Northern Ireland Peace Process, 1984-2006, 1982-2006; 297638
  Materials in this series pertain to the Good Friday Agreement of 1998, marked an historic achievement in Northern Ireland to put an end to the violence which had marked that area for several decades. These files are arranged in chronolical order. Also included are materials, clippings and articles related to the IRA Ceasefire, policing and the RUC, the Orange Parades, and Sinn Fein and Republican Sinn Fein statements.
  - Case Study of Terrorism: Northern Ireland 1970-1990, 299854 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Decommissioning: Commentary and Opinion, 1999-2001; 299967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Decommissioning: Press Clippings, 2000-2001; 299968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Decommissioning: Irish Northern Aid Report, 2001-2002; 299969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Decommissioning: Reports by the Independent Monitoring Commission and the Independent International Commission, 2006; 299970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Consulate General of Ireland, New York - Framework, Feb 1995; 300040 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Framework Press Clippings, Feb 1995-Mar 1995; 300041 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Jerry Adams Visit to US (Clippings), Mar 1995; 300042 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Irish Government Statements, Nov 1995-Apr 1996; 300043 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Mitchell Commission, 1996; 300044 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Manchester Bombing, Jun 1996; 300045 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Durkan Correspondence to Editor of New York Post, Jun 1996; 300046 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Good Friday Agreement: "A New Beginning", Oct 1997; 300047 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Good Friday Agreement: Organization Appeals and Comments, 1996-2001; 300048 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Good Friday Agreement: All Party Talks (The Strands), Jan 1998; 300049 (Box 2, Folder 29)